Jean-Luc Mélenchon is in Savoie,
the 2017 presidential candidate is meeting more and more electors
at different locations in France, to incite them to join the "La France insoumise" movement,
which he created.
Before holding a public meeting in Chambéry,
he went to Albertville, where he visited a hydroelectric central.
Bernard Portugal and Vincent Albrand accompanied him.
Union representants were there to welcome Jean-Luc Mélenchon.
The candidate to the next presidential elections was there to visite this hydroelectric central near Alberville.
He was there for over an hour, the opportunity to speak of energy independence,
but also to reaffirm his opposition to the privatization project
of the hydroelectric dams supported by the European commission.
Nothing will change the efficiency of the dams nor the technical performances of the people there.
And thus there is no reason - if privatization even has one
but it has no other reason than allowing the private sector to benefit from public goods.
End of story!
Jean-Luc Mélenchon continued his visit in Savoie in Chambéry.
He held a press conference and then met with the employees of the company from Isère, "Ecopla",
who attempt for months to regain control of their business, which is in receivership.
We have a company that produces packagings made of aluminium,
and it is the last of the country.
The employees, when the company is being liquidated, say:
We are willing to continue doing what we always did,
i.e running the company,
since it should be underlined that the employees are the ones running the company
and not the capital that was inside.
Since there are people who were ready to retake control of the company,
and since customers were willing to continue working with the company.
Again there is no reason to liquidate the company.
And yet it is being liquidated.
Jean-Luc Mélenchon, who comes for the first time in Chambéry for a meeting,
will be in a few minutes at the Manege convention center.
He will hold a public meeting about his campain
where more than 800 people are expected to attend.